<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Zach Laubach</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:4321/media/icon_hu68170e94a17a2a43d6dcb45cf0e8e589_3079_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A lifecourse approach to investigating developmental plasticity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/development_plasticity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/development_plasticity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am investigating how hyenas&amp;rsquo; social experiences, particularly those occurring early in life, have lasting effects on future phenotypes, DNA methylation, and patterns of aging. Such early-life experiences include maternal social rank, amount of maternal care, and both positive and negative interactions with group mates. Here, I test hypotheses to understand how (e.g., the developmental and mechanistic processes) different types and timings of social experiences ‘get under the skin’ to affect future phenotypes and aging. Given that having high-quality social relationships is a powerful predictor of living a long and healthy life in many species including our own, I also ask similar questions about the role of socioeconomic status and social experiences on patterns of DNA methylation and aging in humans. The significance of this collection of work lies in an unprecedented opportunity to establish a new animal model of aging wherein a persistent social ranking system in spotted hyenas mirrors structurally embedded social hierarchies in humans.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Socioecological determinants of life history traits and fitness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/life_history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/life_history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Currently, I am working to understand how various socioecological factors influence the relationships between life history traits and reproductive success. Using a tractable system of wild barn swallows, I am testing the differential allocation and differential acquisition hypotheses to determine if nestling trait development is subject to constraints that require trade-offs or whether differences in resource access is a primary driver of trait variation. In adult barn swallows, I am using social network methods to understand if patterns of affiliation within and outside of social pair bonds are associated with reproductive success. The significance of this work is the ability to empirically test the well-developed predictions from life-history theory in a wild animal system subject natural selection.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animal responses to changing envirnoments and fitness consequences</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/adaptation_plasticity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/adaptation_plasticity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An area of research that I am developing involves understanding animal responses to changing environments by leveraging the long-term data from the MHP. A rapid increase in urbanization occurring in part of our study cite has exposed hyenas to multiple changes in the selection pressures that differ from those in a natural environment characterized by high lion density and fleet ungulates as primary food sources. As urbanization progresses, competition and death from lions subside and a readily available source of food is easily caught livestock and/or human refuse. I am proposing to test several hypotheses that suggest the release from historic selection pressures across the urbanization gradient affects the phenotype and fitness of hyenas. The significance of this work lies in the ability to disentangle whether trait variation in response to environmental change is driven by evolutionary processes, phenotypic plasticity or both.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mara Hyena Project (est. 1988)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/mhp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/mhp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
